Viktor Yarmak

Age 41

Address 16373 SW 71St Terrace, Miami, FL, 33193

Mobile +1 (786) 816-1974

E-mail viktor.yarmak@gmail.com

Skype vyarmak

LinkedIn http://www.linkedin.com/in/viktoryarmak

Professional summary

Professional with more than 20 years of IT consulting and software development experience in Latin America (Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Mexico), strong technical background (software development, security, infra-structure, telecom) and excellent negotiation and relationship skills.

Field of acting covers acting at all levels of IT department starting from software development till definition of strategy for IT department and product/services to be commercialised.

Strong experience in multidisciplinary team management, including offshore teams.

Worked mainly with markets of e-commerce, financial (cards, internet banking, ATM banking, payment gateways, payment processing), construction, hospital/health care, field services and logistics.

Professional history

Chief Software Architect, Crossover São Paulo, Brasil / Miami, FL – 08.2017 – present

Software architecture definition and implementation based on business and technical requirements.

Mainly used skills: Software architecture definition, Team management, CI/CD definition and implementation, Java (Spring/Spring Boot, Vert.x, J2EE), Jetty, Node.js, React, React Native, Angular.js, PostgreSQL, AWS (ECS, ECR, EKS, EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, DynamoDB, SNS, SQS, CloudWatch, ElasticSearch), RabbitMQ, WebServices, REST, MicroServices architecture definition and implementation, Jenkins, JUnit, Test Driven Development, Open API.

Medici (https://medici.md) - 03.2018 - present

- Definition and implementation of software architecture using Amazon stack (ElasticBeanstalk, ECS, EC2, RDS, SNS, SQS, Redshift, CloudFormation)
- Full stack development with Java (Spring / Vert.x) / Golang / React / Angular
- Management of a team of 5 backend developers
- Definition and implementation of CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins and AWS CloudFormation for Java, Golang and Mobile applications
- Definition and implementation micro service based architecture (breakdown of monolithic application into micro-services)

Smart Park City - 11.2017 - 03.2018

- Definition and implementation of software architecture using Amazon stack (ElasticBeanstalk, EC2, RDS, SNS, SQS, Redshift)
- Full stack development with Java / Spring Boot / React
- Mobile development with React Native

Crossover Chat (internal Crossover project) - 08.2017 - 11.2017

- Definition and implementation of software architecture using Amazon stack (ElasticBeanstalk, EC2, RDS, CloudWatch)
- Full stack development with Go / Node / React
- Mobile development with React Native

Software Architect, RecargaPay

São Paulo, Brasil - 06.2016 - 09.2018

Software architecture definition for new services and migration of currently available services to new architecture. Definition, development and implementation of micro services using AWS based architecture.

Mainly used skills: Java (Spring, J2EE), Jetty, Tomcat, Node.js, Angular.js, PostgreSQL, AWS (EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, DynamoDB, SNS, SQS, CloudWatch, ElasticSearch), RabbitMQ, WebServices, REST, MicroServices architecture, Jenkins, JUnit, Test Driven Development.

Owner, Yarmak Consulting Ltda São Paulo, Brasil – 09.2005 – present

Software development and IT consulting. Business process analysis and consulting. Development, implementation and integration of various IT related projects mainly for e-commerce, loyalty programs, banking (internet banking, online trading, ATM management, mobile banking) and transportation markets.

Mainly used skills: Java (Spring, J2EE), Node.js, Backbone.js, Underscore.js, React, React Native, Ionic, Cordova / Phonegap, Angular.js, Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, AWS (EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, DynamoDB, SNS, SES, SQS, Lambda, CloudWatch, ElasticSearch), Systems integration, Project management

Project manager / Senior consultant, Scopus Tecnologia Ltda. São Paulo, Brazil – 08.2010 – 10.2013

Project manager working with in-house and outsourced multidisciplinary teams, responsible for full project lifecycle, starting from project definition till post implementation support. Definition and follow up of development process, project budgets, timelines. Consulting on e-commerce development, loyalty programs and WAN development.

Management of development, analysis, specification and post-implementation teams in following projects:

- ATM Banking Monitoring System (Jam NM)
 - Analysis, implementation and bug fix of system for ATM monitoring.
 - Currently system monitors nearly 35000 ATM's
 - More than 25000 hours of development / analysis / testing
 - Full lifecycle of software development
 - Support and bug fix of systems that defines amount of cash do be loaded in ATM (99.8% hit rate in normal conditions and 70-80% hit rate in special conditions like holidays, great events, etc.)
- E-Commerce / Loyalty programs
 - Definition of platform and solution architecture, operational workflow and integration between partners of marketplace
 - More than 50000 hours of development / analysis / testing
 - Development of e-commerce portals: Shopping Bradesco Cartões (<u>www.shopfacil.com.br</u>), ShopFácil Veículos (<u>www.shopfacilveiculos.com.br</u>, transformed to www.autoline.com.br), ShopFácil Funcionario (closed), ShopFácil Viagens (<u>www.shopfacilviagens.com.br</u>)
 - Development of portals for loyalty programs: Link 237 (end of program), Bonus Clube (www.programabonusclube.com.br), Visa & Master loyalty program (in development)
 - Integration with partners Walmart, Decolar, Nova Ponto Com, W-Care, Centauro, Netshoes, CompraFácil, Fast Shop, etc.

Consultant, Scopus Tecnologia Ltda. São Paulo, Brazil – 06.2008 – 08.2010

Acting in departments of logistics and internal systems and processes. Principal activities:

- Department of internal systems and processes
 - Software development project management
 - Internalization of software factory of Bradesco Cartões (more than 180 persons)
 - Definition and implementation of mobile solution for field technicians
 - General IT related consulting (areas of software development and infrastructure)
 - Consulting and support on virtualization of production, testing and development environments (more than 250 virtualized servers)
 - Support in other areas (sales, marketing, training)
- Logistics department
 - Analysis of operational process of logistics department
 - Implementation of KPI and improvements in logistics process

IT Department coordinator, Bionexo do Brasil Ltda.

São Paulo, Brasil - 05.2007 - 06.2008

Responsible for definition and implementation of IT department strategy and relationship with foreign offices (Argentina, Spain). Definition and control of budgets of IT department. Definition of architecture, evaluation of possible solutions and implementation of virtualized high availability environment (VMware). Participation in other areas such as: sales, marketing, business development.

Consultant, Scopus Tecnologia Ltda.

São Paulo, Brasil - 09.2005 - 05.2007

Consulting in software development and infra-structure areas, field services process improvements. Responsible for integration between Scopus and Dell, developing and implementing of integration via EDI x.14

CTO, Inteligencia Productiva

Mexico City, Mexico - 07.2003 - 05.2005

Company strategy definition on area of software development. Analysis, definition and creation of new products and services. Responsible for creation of department of software development using local and off-shore teams. Definition of methodology, architecture, frameworks and processes to be used by software development department. Consulting in field of analysis and business process improvement.

Systems Architect / Security consultant, Hexacta

Buenos Aires, Argentina - 04.2000 - 04.2003

Participation in various projects as systems architect / analyst / security consultant.

Technologies used - C, Pro C, C++; Java (EE, EJB, RMI, JSP, JNI, JMS); XML, XSLT, XSD; Oracle, MySQL, Informix, Microsoft SQL; iPlanet, Weblogic, Websphere, JBoss, Tomcat;

Responsible for security of corporate network (Argentina, Brasil, Chile, Mexico, Spain).

Web Developer, Internet Service Provider "Interpoint SRL" / "Desarrollos Digitales" Buenos Aires, Argentina – 10.1999 – 04.2000

Development of web applications using Informix Internet Foundation 2000, PHP, SQL, HTML, JavaScript, PERL, Informix AppPage Builder. Web design (Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Macromedia Dreamweaver, Fireworks, Flash). Application and database servers administration (Linux, Informix, MySQL).

Computing engineer

Slavutych Laboratory of International Research and Technology

Slavutych, Ukraine - 03.1999 - 09.1999

Laboratory network administration, administration of servers with Windows NT, Linux, IRIX (SGI), Digital UNIX (Alpha Servers). Development of web applications for internal use (Perl, CGI, HTML, Java, JavaScript, MySQL, Oracle). User support. Maintenance of "Nuclear database project" servers (under direct management of Pacific Northwest National Laboratory, Brookhaven National Laboratory and Argonne National Laboratory)

Pre-press engineer / Chief of design center, Poligrafiya Ltd Chernigov, Ukraine – 12.1995 – 03.1999

Management of design and printing teams. Budget definition and follow up. Definition of pipeline workflow. Design and pre-press activities.

Education

1994 – 1999	Chernihiv National University of Technology (Chernigov, Ukraine) – Software engineering	Э
1984 – 1994	State school Nº 1 with extensive english learning (Chernigov, Ukraine)	

Languages

Ukrainian and Russian - native English, Spanish, Portuguese - fluent/bilingual